# ZACH BOUDREAUX

#### **SUMMARY**

Motivated software engineering graduate from an intensive 800+ hour boot camp at Springboard with 1 year experience in full stack web development and software development. Seeking work to use proven skills in HTML/CSS, JavaScript (NodeJS, ReactJS, Express), and Python (Flask) for a Washington D.C. area company.

#### **PROJECTS**

Foodly [live link]

Nov. 2021 - Dec. 2021

Second of my two capstone projects. Dynamic, full-stack application utilizing two APIs to search for data on recipes and cocktails and allow you to save these for use later on.

• Front-End [live link]: React.js, JavaScript

• Back-End [live link]: Node.js, Express.js

Movie Database [live link] July 2021 - July 2021

First of my two capstone projects; an app used to search for movies or tv shows where you can see additional data on them and add them to your personal lists

• Front-End: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

• Back-End: Python, Flask

• Database: PostgreSQL, Flask SQLAlchemy

• Extras: Bcrvpt, Flask WTForms

**Jobly [live link]** Sept. 2021 - Sept. 2021

Built a dynamic job finding web application filled with mock data. This works similar to indeed, where you can register or log in, search for jobs in certain companies and then apply to these jobs.

• Front-End [live link]: React.js, JavaScript

• Back-End [live link]: Node.js, Express.js

Warbler [live link] Aug. 2021 - Aug. 2021

Built a Twitter clone that allows you to post tweets, like tweets, and follow other users.

• Front-End: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

• Back-End: Python, Flask

• Database: PostgreSQL

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

FRONT-END LANGUAGES: JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Bootstrap

BACK-END LANGUAGES: Python, Flask, Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, SQL

**CLOUD SYSTEMS:** Heroku: Cloud Application Platform, Surge **TECHNICAL QUALIFICATIONS:** Agile Development, Full Stack

**SOFTWARE:** Git, Homebrew, Microsoft Office Suite, Adobe Software Suite

**OPERATING SYSTEMS:** Windows, Linux (Ubuntu)

## **EMPLOYMENT**

Springboard, Software Engineering Fellow Apr. 2021 - Nov. 2021

- 800+ hour comprehensive Software Engineering Bootcamp
- JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, React.js, Redux JQuery, AJAX, Python, Flask, SQL, HTML, CSS
- Weekly 1-on-1 mentor with an industry professional to help polish my skills
- 4 in-depth portfolio projects

The Compounding Center,
Compounding Pharmacy Technician,
Leesburg, Virginia

Feb. 2020 -Apr. 2021

While at The Compounding Center, I mixed various chemicals to make formulas specific to the patient when the commercial pharmaceuticals didn't fit their needs.

- Quickly became proficient in RxDispense, a pharmacy management software
- Learned how to work independently while also staying efficient with a strong attention to detail

# **EDUCATION**

Springboard Software Engineering Career Track, Certification

Apr. 2021 - Nov. 2021

Software Engineering Fullstack Web Development 2021